Guide to the Dorn Charles McGrath papers, 1973-1987 MS0567.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Dorn Charles McGrath papers
1973-1987
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
McGrath, Dorn Charles
MS0567.UA
6 Linear Feet
Dorn Charles McGrath was the chair and Emeritus Professor of Geography and Urban and Regional Planning. He is also the Director of the Institute for Urban Development Research at The George Washington University (GW). Collection consists of the Machu Picchu project files, correspondence, articles, and personal chronicles. The materials range between 1973 and 1987. The subjects represented are about Machu Picchu and the surrounding areas.
Box UP0001
Box UP0003
Box UP0002
Box UP0005
Box UP0004
Box UP0007
Box UP0006
Box UP0009
Box UP0008
Box UP0010
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated to University Archives by Dorn McGrath in 1987.
Historical or Biographical Note
Dorn Charles McGrath was the chair and Emeritus Professor of Geography and Urban and Regional Planning. He is also the Director of the Institute for Urban Development Research at The George Washington University (GW). His research focused on urban planning, historic preservation, urban environmental Issues, and parks and conservation. He was also the lead researcher for the Loudoun County Environmental Indicators Project (LEIP). McGrath received a B.A. in 1952 from Dartmouth College and a M.C.P. in 1959 from Harvard University.
In 1968, McGrath began his career at GW as an emeritus professor in the Geography Department. He has also has served on many local, national, and international taskforces, committees and advisory groups, and as an inspiring teacher. In 1999 McGrath was appointed to the Solid Waste Transfer Facility Site Selection Advisory Panel for Washington D.C.
In 2003, McGrath retired from GW after 35 years. The same year he received a lifetime achievement award from the Committee of 100 on the Federal City for improving the historical, geographical, and functional aspects of how the Washington metropolitan region looks and works.
McGrath served as President of the American Institute of Planners in 1972, was the chairman for the Committee of 100, and a member of the Middle Atlantic Division of the Association of American Geographiers. In 2003 he was inducted into the American Institute of Certified Planners.
Bib#
8287095
Collection Scope and Content
This collection consists of the Machu Picchu project files, correspondence, articles, and personal chronicles. The materials range between 1973 and 1987. The subjects represented are about Machu Picchu and the surrounding areas.
Geography; Machu Picchu Site (Peru); Peru; George Washington University; McGrath, Dorn Charles
- Carta de Machu Pichu (letter from Machu Picchu): Spanish Edition full set, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Carta de Mach Picchu: seven language set, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Firmontes Meeting: Washington D.C., 08/11/1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Machu Picchu Stationery, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Universidad Nacional Federico Villarreal, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Glusberg/CAYC, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Auq. Ungaro, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Carta de Machu Picchu, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Habitat Documents, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Comparative Analysis of Planning Charters, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Francisco Carbajal, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Charter of Machu Picchu, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Carta de Machu Picchu, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- The Charter of Machu Picchu, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Architecture and National Development Catalog, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Architecture Magazines (6), undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Carta de Machu Picchu, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Americas Articles, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Argentina, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Mexico, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Peru, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Community Planning Report, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- CRIT 6 (Fall), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- CRIT 5 (Spring), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Architectural Record, 01/1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- AIA Journal, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Washington Post, 08/1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- McGrath Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Carta de Machu Picchu, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Charter of Machu Picchu, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Xalapa Memorandum, 05//08/1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Carta de Machu Picchu, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Biennale Bulgaria, 05/1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- DCM Personal Chron, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- DCM Personal Chron, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- DCM Personal Chron, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- DC McGrath Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- McGrath Miscellaneous,Correspondence, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)